

## CONTACT

- @ meagan.ramey@yahoo.
- 608-208-6758
- https://github.com/mea ganramey

Columbia, SC



## EDUCATION

Full Stack Web
Development Certificate
Front-End Web
2021
Development Certificate
2020

EASTERN ILLINOIS
UNIVERSITY
Bachelor of Science in
Biology
2017

# MEAGAN RAMEY

## FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### SUMMARY

Full Stack Software Engineer with hands-on project experience operating remotely with a national team. Lifelong lover of Math, Science, and brain teasers. Dedicated to reading sociology focused books, playing Skyrim, Yu-Gi-Oh!, and Ticket to Ride.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER FACILITATOR

(January 2021-current) FT Contract Position

- Lead workshops to explain and enforce debugging, google foo, problem solving, and other programming skills
- QA Tested, left review comments, and graded submissions

#### KENZIE ACADEMY

(January 2020-January 2021)

Software Development | Project Based Training | Indianapolis, IN (Remote)

- Excelled in an intensive 12-month technical engineer training, earning front-end and full stack certification with over a 98% each quarter
- Gained proficiency in JavaScript and Python languages and frameworks, like React and Django, SQL and NoSQL databases, many other tools and technologies, including MongoDB, Node.js, and Express
- OOP, development, testing and debugging, designing interfaces, and building efficient algorithmic business solutions
- Productive and efficient member of remote team. Gathered requirements, met deadlines, and created real world applications involving virtual environments, unit testing, OOP, building and connecting to 3<sup>rd</sup> party RESTFUL API, web requests, and user authentication systems.
- Hands-on project-based experience:
  - Spark, a new take on a dating app, in a 4-person team, which implemented authentication, CRUD operations, class-based views, custom users, and custom Django admin commands utilizing Django and Python.
  - Power Talkers Scrum Master and developer on a 4person team using MERN stack, deployed with Firebase, authentication and state managed by Firebase, Front-End created with Axios, React Router Dom and Bootstrap

# TECHNICAL SKILLS



React



Redux



**JavaScript** 



Git



MongoDB



**Firebase** 



Node / Express



Material UI / Bootstrap / Tailwind Python







E3

HTML / CSS



**VS** Code



Slack

**QA** Testing

# MEAGAN RAMEY

# FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- <u>Twitter Clone</u> Project Manager and developer in a 3person project team which implemented many features such as authentication, CRUD operations, and Google login utilizing React, Axios, and Redux (March 2021 – Built a <u>new Twitter Clone</u> in 2 days by myself using Zustand for state management)
- E-commerce side project using MERN stack. Expanded proficiencies in React, managing state with Zustand, Express, Material UI, and JSON Web Token

#### SOFTWARE FNGINFER TUTOR

(May 2020-January 2021) PT Contract Position

- Developed learners rich understanding in basic and intermediate React, Node.js, MongoDB, Express, JavaScript, and HTML / CSS
- Provided meaningful feedback that led to changes in weekly operations and specific plans for struggling students to succeed.

#### SURGICAL SERVICES SUPPORT SPECIALIST

(August 2017-May 2019) Franciscan Alliance, Indianapolis, IN

- Pulled and analyzed data, and organized into shareable data points for monthly, quarterly, and yearly metrics
- Collaborated with physicians on process improvements utilizing cost saving data metrics
- Managed daily schedules, dictated meetings, worked on individual and team projects

#### REFERENCES

DR. ANGFLA GLAROS

Eastern Illinois University, Professor of Anthropology 217-581-3123 acalaros@eiu.edu

DR. KURT TERRELL

Franciscan Alliance, Medical Director of Anesthesiology

317-371-9635 <u>drkurt.terrell@franciscanalliance.org</u>

VINCE ST. LOUIS

GovSpend, Senior Full Stack Engineer

704-759-4517 vincentst.louis@amail.com

**GWEN FARADAY** 

Rocketbuild, Senior Software Engineer / Kenzie Academy, MERN Curriculum Developer

317-363-2915 gwenfaraday@pm.me